Hello. Hello everyone and welcome to the
brand new series.
Yu-Gi-Oh!
Power of Chaos: Yui The Destiny.
Everyone,
we are finally playing a Yu-Gi-Oh game I
have no experience with. It is a very
rare occasion where we play a Yu-Gi-Oh
game where I'm going in blind. So,
because this is a PC game, I am not too
familiar with this. I'm going to ask you
all to be patient with me. And I say,
let's just see what this game is like.
We have match duel, single duel, replay,
and tutorial. Well, I know how to play
Yu-Gi-Oh, so let's try a single duel.
I wonder how strong your deck is.
Actually, it doesn't matter because I'll
use all my skills to defeat you, no
matter how many powerful cards you have
in your deck.
>> Oh, it has real voice acting and
animation. Oh, baby. Select your hand. I
choose paper. Ah, you got me. All right,
Yugi, you're pretty good already. I
could see. Let's start the duel.
Oh, by the way, there was no way to
change options. Oh my god, this is the
oldest. I got the Dark Magician. That's
really good. These are the oldest cards.
a card.
>> Oh, he actually talks.
>> I end my turn.
>> He legitimately talks. What the hell?
All right, draw phase. I got the
legendary beaver warrior. All right,
let's try to get him. I'm going to
summon the man-eating treasure chest.
>> No.
What am I supposed to do? All I have are
monsters. Holy crap. How old is this
game? Is this going to be just the
original Yu-Gi-Oh cards? Like the Oh,
he's using Mammoth Graveyard.
He's got beaver warrior 2. Oh, thank god
I have sorcerer of the doomed. That's
going to be how I make a comeback.
Oh my god. So, my life points are down
here. That's so interesting.
>> Yugi talks to me.
Celtic guardian. That's actually pretty
good. Actually, we're going to use
Celtic Guardian cuz that's just one of
the classics that I love. Uh yeah, let's
go ahead and go to battle phase. I can
figure this out. This isn't too
complicated. I attack beaver war. I can
move the sword. Oh my god. I attack
beaver warrior.
Ha, I got your legendary beaver warrior.
Yugi, let's see what you can do now.
[Music]
>> Oh, he's scared.
>> I switch it to defense position. I end
my turn.
>> All right. Yi's feeling fear. I can see
that now. Oh, I have Pauly. Wait, what
are my fusions? I can make metal dragon.
Oh my god, I just need lesser dragon or
a fusion substitute. That's a really
cool fusion monster. Okay, I'm done
looking at that now. Can I How do I put
that away? Oh, there we go. Right click.
Right click puts that away. Uh, let's go
ahead and summon. Actually,
[Music]
I'm going to do No, I didn't want to
sum. I wanted to set. Oh god, I don't
know how to set. Oh dear lord. Oh dear
lord. No, no, I didn't want to put in
defense mode. Oh my god. What am I
doing? Oh god. Oh god. I've messed up
everything. I don't know how to play the
game. Is right click set. Is that what
it is?
Oh, he's got feral lamp. I just I just
killed myself. He has manear plug. There
was no reason to do anything.
>> My Celtic guardian to attack position.
>> Yugi, I'm I'm just a beginner. I don't
know what I'm doing. Maybe I should have
done the tutorial. Holy crap.
I'm so used to other games where I click
the card and it says summoner set. This
time it's just literally like do it.
Well, I got to draw lesser dragon or I'm
going to die. Heart of the cards draw.
Well, that's not bad either. Oh my god,
that's Skull Red Bird. That's a really
good card. I summon Skull Redbird. I go
into battle phase. I attack your
maneater bug for,00 damage.
>> Attack. Yeah, your other monsters don't
scare me cuz my sorcerer kit has more
attack than you. If only I got two
monsters out, I could dark magician or
any other spell and trap cards.
>> No.
>> Yes. This I was waiting for. I monsters
as a tribute. I'm counting on you. I
summon Dark Magician.
>> Oh, this is so cool. What the hell? This
game's all How did I miss this game as a
kid? It's cuz it was a PC game and I
grew up with PlayStation, so what do you
expect? I end my turn.
>> Oh my god, I need a busted spell or trap
card. It's too late for trap hole,
though. Oh man, how do I set?
No, I don't want to end my turn. I want
to set my card. Oh, there we go. Oh,
right click to change. I gotcha. I
gotcha. I figured it out. Okay, game
one. We're going to lose. It's fine.
This is freaking awesome. I find Yui
freaking Mudo and he's so cool. God damn
it. He's so cool. He's got the beaver
warrior. I got the beaver warrior. Okay,
wait. We could abuse the AI. He went for
maximum damage, which would have ended
the duel.
>> He was going for game, but he doesn't
have enough game. Even if I do get my
fusion now, it won't save us. So, we
need a powerful spell or trap card
>> or monster effect. Ah, that's a nice
one, but it's not useful right now. I
think the duel's over. I don't have
enough defense. He'll just summon
another monster. I summon my sorcerer of
the doomed. And with my last play, I
attack your beaver warrior.
Oh, if I didn't misplay or miss well, if
I knew the controls a little bit better,
I could have changed this duel a little
bit, but he was he's the king of games
for a reason. He knows what he's doing.
He got his legendary Dark Magician out.
Oh, Mystic Clown. One of the strongest
cards from back in the day. Yep. You
think I'm joking? The clowns always
demanded power.
Dark magic attack. He got me. I'm okay
with that. I I got to learn a little bit
about the game and I enjoyed it.
>> Would you like to save the duel? No.
God, no. They're watching it on YouTube.
>> That was an excellent duel. I'm lucky I
was able to draw the right cards at the
right time.
>> Starting Trap Hole and getting Yeah. No,
that was cool, Yugi. That was really
cool. I love the voice acting. What the
hell? This is great. All right, let's
try again. Um, I assume if I win, I
might get new cards. Uh, so let's just
keep trying. It's going to be Yugi,
right? You've come prepared because it's
time to duel.
>> Well, I just learned how to sit last
episode or last fight. So, now I know
what I'm doing. And you like scissors,
so I choose rock. Son of a How are you
so good at that? A He's too good. Since
he gets to go first, unless he let me go
first. Trap cards are his advantage.
Oh, I got Dark Magician again. And I got
way better a way better hand. All right.
I summon the Mystic Clown to bait out a
stronger monster from you, if you could
even find one. Dragon zombie
surprisingly is one. God, that means
effect monsters must be rare in this
game. Oh, he did have one. Uh-uh. I
chain.
>> Oh no,
>> he said something. Oh my god, this is so
cool.
>> I freaking love you, dudes.
>> All right, you end your turn. Well, then
I draw. That's a really good card. I'm
afraid he'll have his own trap hole, but
trapole.
>> God damn it. I didn't exactly have a
choice. I'll set this.
I'm running out of options now cuz if he
gets another powerful monster. I swear
all these cards we're seeing are like
from the starter decks
when the game first came out. The if you
ever had start Yugi, Joey, uh Kaiba, and
Pegasus.
Yeah, he just had two. Lucky bastard.
I have to hope he goes for a tribute
summon next turn. Otherwise, I'm in
trouble.
>> I end my turn.
>> Damn. How did you start with two Neos? I
draw. That card's useless.
All right. Oh, I forgot to say. Okay.
Well, I haven't learned anything
apparently. I'm still thinking like I'm
playing a different Yu-Gi-Oh game where
I click the card, then I click what I
want to do. I got to slow down. Oh, Dark
Hold just gained value. I'll say that
much. But I have two bricks in my three
well, two bricks in my hand. So, it's
not great. It's not great. I need to
draw a decent monster. or whether it's
decent attack or decent defense.
>> I can actually summon Silver Fang. Not
the best, but it'll have to do.
>> You're going to activate a spell card.
>> I activate Dark Hole.
And then I summon the Silver Fang. Go my
monster. Halloween Strike.
>> Not bad.
>> Thanks, Yug. Now I'm going to end my
turn. He still has advantage by a lot
because this is terrible. This field is
terrible.
Ah, Celtic Guardian.
I drew some powerful cards, but he drew
two 17 beaters in his opening hand.
>> And in this game, just having the bigger
monster is all that matters. I draw. Oh,
I drew it. The maneating treasure chest.
You're going down, Celtic Guardian, for
your greed trying to eat my treasure.
>> That was a good attack.
>> Thank you.
All right, the good news is I got the
kill. The bad news is it's a top deck
game at this point. I've already used
all my best options.
Okay, good news. He's setting my turn.
>> I need more monsters though. Something
decent.
That's one way to get another monster.
Let's force his hand. I activate change
of heart
>> spell card.
>> This is one of the best cards in the
game. I want your card.
It's a freaking maner bug. He almost had
me. I summon the ultimate monster by
tributing two monsters.
[Music]
A tribute summon. He's freaking out. I
attack with the dark magician.
I love the little comic panels. What the
hell? They're actually animated, too.
That's great. This is great. This game's
so cool.
Ah, you're just going to set like a
coward.
>> End my turn. I could sit here all day
playing Yugi. Let's see. Celtic
Guardian. That's a good one. All right,
I'm going to summon this. I can't win
the duel anyway. So, no, I'm not going
to play my trap card right now. That's
for emergencies. I can't win the duel
this turn anyway. So, let's use Dark
Magician.
No, not yet. Oh, good choice.
Holy crap. We destroyed one of the
strongest cards in the game.
Unironically,
one more attack and you're done for you.
This duel is almost mine.
That's a pretty good card. And no, it's
fine. I will allow my monster to die.
However, if I don't top deck another
monster next turn, I will lose. I will
not win the duel. I need one more
monster card.
>> I end my turn.
>> Dragon zombie is pretty good, Yug. But
watch this. I top deck lesser. I have
the fusion. Ah, that's cool. I summon
lesser dragon, which is all I need to
win this duel. I owned her battle phase.
Dark magic attack.
>> A Yugi, I'm sorry, but this time I
played a little better. And by that I
mean I drew Dark Hole and I keep getting
Dark Magician. 1,200 damage.
Not bad.
Would you like to save? No. I just want
to see what I get for winning a duel.
Win a card. All right. What' I get? Uh,
that might be better than some of the
stuff I own.
I'm proud of you. Your skills have
greatly improved. I can see that you'll
make an excellent duelist.
>> Thanks, Yuges. That's really nice of
you. All right. Well, then let's go to
deck construction and figure out what
that new card can do for me. So, let's
see. What do I not need?
Um, out of all of these cards, my worst
card is Well, I have some really good
ones here. I'm not even though these
guys are terrible, I I really want to go
for the
for the fusion. I feel like it'd be
really cool to get the the metal dragon
off. It's nice that the game starts you
with a cool fusion. Uh most of these
cards actually do have a use,
but that new card I pulled would be more
useful.
Sorry, that's not what I meant. I would
like to put this in the trunk if I could
and then take this out of the trunk
because this works with my equip spell.
Yeah, actually we could put it over here
if we could. No. Okay. Well, it doesn't
matter to me. I'm guessing. What does
this do? Oh, I could search for cards.
Okay. Well, I'm guessing I don't have a
I have to earn it one. Well, there was
that other mode. Let's see. Import or
export. No, thank you. Uh I'm going to
earn them myself. What is uh the other
mode? It said match duel. Let's try
that.
>> I hope you've come prepared because it's
time to duel.
>> Yeah, I've upgraded my deck, Yugi. Let's
see what you got.
All right, try scissors. Okay, try fist.
Damn, he's smart. He let me go first,
though. That was very kind of him. All
right, let's do this again. Let's see
what you got, Yukes. Okay, I got a
mystical elf and a two-pronged attack.
Mystical elf is a great start,
especially since I have two tributes.
And I actually remembered to set that
time instead of summoning like a fool.
I probably should just play two-pronged
attack, but I did not yet. Ah, he gets
so many Neos in his deck. Gosh darn it.
It's stronger than everything I own.
That isn't a tribute monster.
>> All right,
>> I'll set a card.
>> He has a set, too.
>> End my turn.
>> A normal summon probably doesn't work
then.
[Music]
Well, if I'm going to sacrifice a card,
I summon you to see if he has trap hole.
>> Okay, let's get rid of the trap hole
then.
That's a shame, but we had to do what we
had to do. I'm going to end my turn
there. Yuges, do not tribute
or fuse.
>> I activate my spell card.
>> He has plot agreed.
>> Oh, damn.
>> I end my turn.
>> All right. Well, I have to kill that
face down or else he'll get a big
tribute off. Skull Redbird's my best
chance. Let's do it.
I summon Skull Redbird. I will not use
that trap until absolutely necessary. I
attack your monster.
>> Flip.
>> Ah, if that gets
>> all monsters attack triggered my effect.
>> All right, might as well. I'm going to
lose everything anyway. I trigger
two-pronged attack.
>> Yeah. Chain in the oldest Yu-Gi-Oh game.
I designate that monster. I designate
that monster. I destroy this monster.
There was actually a chain link. What
the hell? The attack still went through,
so you died. All right, I I have to rely
on Celtic Guardian now. I lost some of
my best cards. I was going to lose them
anyway, so why not?
[Music]
He better not have an aro. Okay, at
least it's a it'll be a fair fight.
He has a bigger hand than I do, though,
so I need to figure something else out.
>> End my turn.
>> Part of the cards.
Yes, I top decked dragon zombie. My
buddy Bones's favorite monster.
Actually, it's probably pumpkin, but
either way, get attacked on.
It's one of my favorites.
>> That was a good
>> from Bones's deck. All right, 200 damage
will be dealt. I end my turn. Come on,
you.
[Music]
Okay,
>> I end my turn.
>> We got him to play passively. That's
really good. As long as he doesn't have
mystical elf.
I could do it again. I activate change
of heart spell card.
>> I could have saved this for later, but
honestly, I don't want you to get in our
trapole or anything. Or another
maneater. How did you get two? Your mom
lets you have two maneater bugs. All
right. I tribute your maneater bug and
my
>> summon.
>> Yeah. And my dragon.
I summon the dark magician.
I attack for 25.
Ah,
>> there must be something I can do.
>> You felt that one. Only a dark hole can
stop me now. Nice to have Kelsey
Guardian.
The legend.
All right, a set.
>> I end my turn.
>> Part of the cards. Give me something
good.
That's pretty good. Actually, I'm going
to go with Celtic Guardian just in case
cuz he might summon a monster stronger.
We're going to go to battle phase and
we're going to let Dark Magician handle
the defense mode monster. Yeah, it was
12 again. What the hell? What are the
odds of that? I attack for 14.
>> Not bad.
>> Thanks, Hugs. I end my turn.
All right, next player's turn. Let's see
what he's got.
All he has is a set. That's not going to
matter.
>> All right, Yuki. Let's watch this. I
draw lesser tra. Oh, I just need Paulie.
I summon Sorcerer of the Doomed.
I attack.
I could have game right now. I attack.
Oh, I beat it by 50. Holy crap. Feral
limp falls to my sorcerer's attack.
>> There must be something I can do.
>> No.
>> What?
>> It's too late now. Yukes. Celtic
guardian. Take him out.
[Music]
>> Game one goes to us.
All right. Nope. It was a good duel, but
no thank you. That's one win for us. I
want to see what we earn if we get two.
Do we get like a whole pack of cards or
maybe just multiples? Uh, I don't have
anything to swap. Well, I guess I could
if I had a side deck, but screw that.
Ah, I'm going second this time. Starting
trapole would be strong.
Oh, I have giant soldier. I have change
of heart and monster abore. Damn, these
are some of the strongest cards in the
game.
>> I end my turn.
>> Problem is, he keeps getting the same
beater monster that I can't beat.
Stronger than every card I own. This is
not a bad beater, but it's just not
strong enough. I set the giant soldier
of stone, the one of the strongest cards
from back in the day. Level three with
insane stats.
Unless I draw a tribute, we're in
trouble. Feral limp.
Uh, I get some deflected damage.
That was a good attack.
>> It was a defense, but okay.
>> I end my turn.
>> Oh, I need to top deck something really
good before he tributes. Ah, if only I
had silver fangs fusion, but I need dark
world thorns and the fusion monster.
I can't let him tribute summon. So, I'm
going to have to sacrifice my elf. But
my elf can take down the imp.
Go attack.
[Music]
>> That was,
>> you know, he has dark magician in his
hand. He's freaking Yuki Mudo or Yami
Yuki, whoever you want to call him.
Oh, that's the first time an enemy Oh,
he's going to set and it's going to be a
flip effect monster and it's going to
win him the duel.
>> I activate my spell card.
>> Wait, main phase two.
Okay, maybe the AI is just being nice to
me.
>> With this card, I can't fail. I offer a
monster on my field as a tribute. I call
forth my summon sky.
>> No.
Oh my god. Oh my god.
That's That's got to be the best card in
this game. Oh, and I got trapped one
turn too late. I can't fight the summon
skull.
Oh man, I have to draw a single tribute
monster, which I do have. It's just
uncommon of I have to kill that summon
skull. Dragon Zombie. I It's already too
late to get rid of Summon Skull, but I
can at least stop his advance.
He's probably just going to go after
Giant Soldier anyway. Yeah.
Oh, I'm running out of time. I need to
draw
>> any tribute monster. Oh crap.
>> End my turn.
>> Either way, I have to draw a new tribute
monster.
Malf is good. It's just not good enough.
Oh my gosh,
this guy's cheating. That's one of the
best cards in the game, if not the best,
cuz I don't know if Jinszo exists yet.
It probably doesn't given how old this
game feels. Please don't attack in the
correct order. Oh, good. We got lucky.
We got lucky.
>> 400 deflected. We got to work on those
life points. I don't know what that
trap's going to be, though, so I'm kind
of worried.
>> I need any way of destroying that thing.
>> A draw.
Okay. Okay. Well, a crash play is the
best play I have, but they might have
trap hole.
They don't have trap hole. It's probably
two-pronged to attack then. I attack
your monster.
It's the only way to slow them down.
Either way, I'm running out of time
here.
I hope I can get pot of greed or
something of that value. Damn, he got a
stronger card. My beaver warrior.
my life points.
Oh no.
>> Part of the cards. Give me something I
can actually use.
That's nothing.
I have one more turn before I have to
use any of the cards in my hand. All
right, Yuges. I have one top deck left.
Let's see what you draw.
>> I've finally broken all the magical
seals. What?
>> I call forth the unstoppable Exodus.
>> What? That's impossible.
>> Nobody's ever been able to summon him.
Are you serious?
Did I just get Exodioed on in episode
one?
Oh, that is ridiculous.
I didn't stand a chance.
The man pulled Exodia on me. Damn. No, I
don't want to go second. I I had the
choice. Oh crap. Oh crap. I just screwed
myself. Going second is a huge
disadvantage. I actually got my spell
card this time, but no dark monsters.
>> I activate my spell card.
>> Okay,
trap.
>> I end my turn. I draw.
I can't believe I just got Exodia on.
That was ridiculous.
If he has summoned skull again, I have
to kill that monster, which means I have
to sacrifice my best defender, but that
was his plan all along.
I could also just set up Manor Bbug if
I'm so worried about summon skull again,
but then again, I'm just going to go for
it. It's fine.
It's one of my best cards. I might as
well use it. He's guaranteed to kill it
next turn.
But once I draw a dark monster, I'll be
able to power it up. And then you're
going down.
>> I activate my spell card.
>> What now?
>> Right. Gekki.
>> Oh, that's that's got to be it. Oh no,
that's a flip effect. Why else would he
set when I'm wide open?
>> I might as well sacrifice silver. Oh, I
got my new card. That's my new card that
works with my equip spell. It's all
coming together, folks.
I edited my deck for this exact match.
But now I know I'm on a time li What?
I just got outplayed.
Oh, even with my equip spot, I'd never
kill that.
I'm on a time limit now cuz now I know
he has Exodia.
>> I end my turn.
>> He's not going to reveal it. [__] I
can't hit him. Celtic guardian can help
though. I summon Celtic Guardian.
Celtic guardian, you attack.
>> Flip.
>> You're dead.
>> Your monster's attack triggered my
effect.
>> Yeah, I lost him. That was a good play.
That's what I thought would happen last
turn, but I didn't get that. All right,
end my turn. First duel is not going
horribly or great. It's just a It's just
a even game.
Beaver Warrior is pretty good, but he
won't Damn it. He won't put his giant
soldier in a different mode.
I end my turn. To
>> kill Beaver Warrior would cost me my
equip spell.
Oh, I have a better idea.
I set my own Beaver Warrior and I hope
he tributes.
Come on, Yuges. Bring out your best
monster.
Damn it. This is fine. At least
at least now I contribute. If I get a
tribute monster
>> attack,
>> it was good defense, but thank you
anyway. I end my turn.
>> Very kind of you, Yuki. Very kind.
The mystic clown. That's even better.
It's not enough though to beat the giant
soldier, but he'll beat that beaver
warrior into the ground. I love clowns
after all. Mystic clown go. Now, this
dark sword will could buff you up, but
it's not time for that. Also, I'm pretty
sure he got too many earbugs, so I'm
mentally preparing for that.
And now you can't attack for three
whole.
>> No. Did you get swords?
>> Revealing light.
>> Oh, that's one of the strongest spells.
All these old school Yu-Gi-Oh cards are
insanely powerful.
Swords is a good play. I'll give you
that.
>> But you weren't expecting this, were
you?
>> I activate a spell card.
>> Spell.
I'm not going to just let you hide
behind your swords, Yugi. Of course, I
still need to attack you. So, I'm going
to use
I like Beaver Warriors defense. I don't
know if I want to set up Manor Bug just
yet. I mean, it would get past Giant
Soldier, but I want to have an option
later, too. I don't know.
Maybe I could bait him into attacking me
if I set another monster. I set Lesser
Dragon
and Mr. Clown will attack one of the
faceowns.
Okay. Well, he got a very lucky hand.
We're taking a lot of deflected damage
this duel,
but he hasn't drawn a tribute yet, which
is why we still have a chance.
>> I end my turn.
>> He didn't even have a monster. Even
better.
Ooh, that's pretty good. Only a dark
hole scares me now since he already
reggied. I didn't even know about
Regeki.
He's just what? He's just got all the
soul in the world. He's got the
strongest cards ever. He's going to get
Exodia again. I don't want to lose to
Exodia twice in one episode.
Come on, game.
>> I end my turn.
>> Part of the cards.
That's not terrible, but it I I just
can't beat him. I don't have anything
strong enough.
And the best I do have is a freaking
manear bug, which can only kill one out
of three of the problems.
Please give me something that could stop
a chance at Exodia. Plus, he got it
super early last time. Like an insane
end.
>> Lucky Exodia.
All right, I draw monster. I don't think
there's anything that strong in the
grave. Yeah, nothing with 2,000 attack.
Yeah, I'm done looking at my grave.
Thank you. I want to look at his.
Nothing.
All right, clown. I want you to go first
and find out what this is.
>> Flip.
>> All right. Well, as long as he hits
Mystic Clown triggered my effect,
>> that was a really, really good guess.
Holy crap. That was a great guess by
Yugi. Come on, fight me, Yugi. Tribute
your monsters. Don't get Exodia again.
Celtic guardian is fine. I'm fine with
that. Even if it kills lesser dragon,
I'm fine with it.
All I'm waiting on is my tribute
monsters.
Do I even have summon skull or
something? Oh, I can get up to 2,000
attack, but that's still not enough.
All right, I need just a little more
damage.
I attack.
>> Not bad.
>> If I could just muster a few more attack
points, I'd win. But I can't pull it off
right now.
I'm saving my trap holes for when he
gets out a big monster.
That one is actually kind of big now
that I look at it.
Fair enough. That's worth a trap hole.
>> No, I don't want to activate both trap
holes. Thank you very much.
>> End my turn.
>> Come on, Dark Magician. I need you. This
is the end of the match. It's the third.
Oh, that only slows him down. It doesn't
defeat him. Still,
if I could just get it. I might be able
to clear the field.
>> I've finally broken all the shields. I
couldn't get past 42. I freaked that.
>> Double Exodiac.
>> I lost the match.
>> I got a double Exodia on. And the first
one was luck. The first one was pure
luck. He didn't even draw that much. The
second one he just stalled for it. Damn
it.
Just too many defenders.
Oh god. I mean, that was No,
I'm not even going to win a card then.
>> You still need a lot of work to hone
your dueling skills. You should start
over and reconstruct your deck.
>> I don't own any cards, Yugi. Don't you
get it? I'm poor in this game. We have
no cards to reconstruct. All right, it's
fine, guys. Next episode, we're going to
just focus on getting new cards. That
way, we can actually make a proper deck.
See you all then. I hope you enjoyed the
introduction of Yu-Gi-Oh! Power of
chaos.